詹姆斯·肯恩
塔斯黛·韦尔德
大盗独行
联袂主演
罗伯特·普罗斯基
詹姆斯·贝鲁什
汤姆·西尼奥雷利
威利·纳尔逊
这有辆从查尔斯顿来的黑车 他们正在追这个人
It's a hot car from Charleston. They're running a name check on him now.
- 呼叫马修斯 - 这是偷来的 或者丢失的
- Calling Matthews... - It's stolen or missing.
追捕抢劫犯和逃犯
Wanted for robbery and escape...
福特 四门的 你能确定是Melrose还是
Ford, uh, four-door. Can you make it to Melrose and...
在北区
It's the north-side zone. It's...
每秒400米
1,300 feet a second?
看32号能不能逮到他
See if 32 has got him.
导 演
迈克尔·曼
搞定了没
Are you clear?
我们这刚发生了一起抢钱包的
We have a purse snatch that's just occurred...
知道了
You're clear here.
搞定了 快
Yeah. Come on.
- 早上好 - 嘿 早上好
- Mornin'. - Yeah, mornin'.
怎么样 船长
What to it, Captain?
冷
Cold.
冷的时候马鲛鱼就出来活动了
Mackerel run when it's cold.
要不要来个酥皮饼
You want a Danish?
好啊
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
好吃吧
Look at that, huh?
嗯
Hmm.
美味
That's magic.
伙计 知道现在什么流行吗
That's what that is, man.
是Sky Chief
That's the Sky Chief.
知道Sky Chief这东西吗
Ain't that Sky Chief somethin'? Huh?
嗯 知道
Yeah.
当真
You bet.
哟 布鲁斯
Yo, Bruce.
想在最后一个交易日把这些都卖掉 把它挪到前面那条线上去
Want to finish cleanin' up that LTD? Move it up to the front line.
绿色奔驰移走
Get rid of this green Merc.
嘿 布鲁斯
Hey, Bruce.
把这辆林肯MK4停到线后面去
Park the Mark IV under the lights.
约翰
Hey, John!
把角落的那辆捷豹留给我 好吗
Spot this Cougar on the corner for me, will ya?
甜心 车管局的所有权转让书发来了吗
Hey, sugar, those transfer titles come in from the Vehicle Bureau?
没有 拉尔夫被坏了引擎的克莱斯勒烦死了
Nope. Ralph got tied up on the Chrysler with the cracked block.
- 帮我找巴里 - 他也有些事要忙
- Get Barry for me, will you? - He also had to drop some parts
你要让他去打点自助洗衣店
and you wanted him to make the laundromat collection?
- 嗯 - 巴里 等一下
- Yeah. - Barry? Hold on.
- 找到他了 - 嗯
- You got him? - Yeah, 232.
嘿 听着 我不知道要跟那人去多久
Hey. Listen, I don't know how long I'm gonna be with the man
帮我个忙 去趟车管局
so do me a favour and swing by the Vehicle Bureau
用我的名字拿些所有权转让书 行吗
and pick up some transfer titles in my name, all right?
拜拜
Bye. Bye,
手伸出来
Put your hand out.
早上好啊 弗兰克 怎么没见你进来 要不要早餐
Morning, Frank. Didn't see you come in. Would you like breakfast?
咖啡就行 谢谢
No, just some coffee, thanks.
谢谢
Thank you.
太棒了
All right!
搞到多少
What do you make it?
嗯 59个
It's, uh, 59
从完美无瑕到有极少瑕疵的各个品级都有
D flawless to VSI 1.
你能拿一个 半个克拉到三个克拉左右的
You got a one and a half to three-carat spread.
批发价550000 我拿185000
$550,000 wholesale. I'll take $185,000.
- 我要了 - 好
- I'll take it myself. - Fine.
明早有些人要去看看 这些人想见你
Have someone swing around tomorrow morning. Look, these people want to meet you.
什么
What?
都是些信得过的家伙
They're stand-up guys.
- 我和别人有约 我还要去他妈的乡村俱乐部 - 好好
- I want to meet people, I'll go to a fuckin' country club. - Okay, okay.
顺便说一下 你想让我把你的情况公之于众
You want me to put some of your end out on the street?
巴里会处理这些的
Barry will collect it.
今天下午三点你把钱给他
You down the bread to him at 3:00 this afternoon.
三个月内 你会让你的钱翻一番
You'll double your money in three months.
我的钱在银行里安全得很
My money goes in the bank.
你的钱在大街上还不知道是谁的
You put your money on the street.
嘿 账单给我
Hey, give me the check.
得了吧
Forget it.
晚上一起吃晚饭
Listen, we having dinner tonight?
好
Yeah.
新毛衣 挺漂亮
That's a new sweater. It's nice.
哦 谢谢
Oh. Yeah, thanks.
- 八点来接你 - 再见
- Then I'll pick you up at eight. - Bye.
嗯 等他回来的时候
Tell him to, uh, see me
叫他来见我
the minute he gets, uh, back here
嗯
and, uh...
好
Sure.
太热了
...shit under a hot rock, man.
嘿 弗兰克 干吗来了 老板
Hey, Frank, Frank, Frank. What's doin', boss man?
嘿 把我的扳手拿来
Hey, give me my wrench back!
给你 不过不是你给我的那个大扳手
Here's your tool. Not the mama one you gave me.
该死的 没工具不能干活
Can't work without a tool, Goddamnit.
- 我尽力了 - 我看你才没尽力
I try my best. I see you didn't do it.
"这儿没什么新鲜事
"Nothing new ever happens around here
过你想过的日子
making your life happen
清点你的外债
like you said
我会去看你
collecting your debt back from society
你在俄克拉荷马州的笔友"
I gotta see ya. Your pal, Okla."
"来看你"
"Gotta see ya."
就在此时 亚利桑那州的参议员
In a moment, Arizona senator denies as false and libellous
否认了他与黑社会有染等损害他名誉的传言
rumours that he has connections with the underworld.
新闻时分 1:02
News time, 1:02.
- 全都给我吧 - 好
- Gimme a total, will ya? - All right.
- 对了 巴里来找过你 - 什么时候
- Oh, Barry's been callin' you. - When?
记不清了 半小时前来了好几次
I don't know. Couple of times last half hour.
- 什么 - 三次
- What? - Three times.
号码是532-9234
532-9234.
- 给我用下电话 - 好
- Gimme the phone, will ya? - Yeah.
喂
Hello?
- 你在哪 - 你到底在哪
- Where are you? - The hell you been?
- 你去勾搭妹纸了 - 我在这该死的电话亭里
- You make the pick-up? - I'm in a God damn phone booth.
找个本地电话 听着 我没出来泡妞
Trying to find a phone that works in this city. I have not made the pick-up.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
方便说话吗
Can you talk?
- 不方便 你见到我们的人了吗 - 没见到 因为这没人
- No. You see our man? - No, 'cause there was no man.
盖格思出去散步 路过他十二楼的窗户
Gags took a walk through his twelfth-story window.
在人行道上被水泼了一身
He's splattered all over the sidewalk.
你想干嘛
What do you want to do?
他留下我们的货了吗
Did he down our merch?
他走了 带着现金 什么
Is he gone? Did he carry the cash on him? What?
我不是正和你说着他吗
I'm talking to somebody's somebody.
二十五分钟内我会知道的
I will know in 25 minutes.
找辆能用的车 在阿米蒂奇和林肯市和我见面
Get the work car and meet me at Armitage and Lincoln.
杰米 给你
Jimmy, here, here.
盖格思正暗地里给这个
On the side, Gags was laying down juice loans
阿泰格利亚放高利贷 对吧
on the street for this Attaglia, right?
他本应该上交这些高额利息
He was turning in the vig money
但他把本金都放进自己口袋里了
but he was putting in his pocket the principal.
他们发现盖格思一直在欺骗他们
They found out he was screwing 'em over.
- 他们真疯狂 - 砰嗙
They went crazy. Ba-boom.
- 盖格思留下我们的货了吗 - 是的 在RD休息室
- Gags down our march'? - Yeah. At the RD. Lounge.
泡利看到了
Paulie saw it go down.
盖格思跑路时 他口袋里的钱是你的
It was your money in Gags' pocket when he went out the window.
你继续维持住
You keep this runnin'.
有什么需要帮助的
Can I help you?
哦 是的 我想见
Yes, please. I'd like to see a Mr...
- 我要一杯咖啡 - 好的 你的杯子在哪
- I want a cup too. - Sure. Where's your cup?
- 机器后面 - 非常抱歉 您刚才说了什么
Back by the machine. I'm sorry. What were you saying?
哦 我想见阿泰格利亚先生
Yes. Mr. Attaglia. I'd like to see him.
你交付了一批电镀件 我有些疑问
You've made a delivery of some plating, and I had a lot of problems with it.
请稍等
Just a minute.
这儿有人要见你 是电镀件的事情
There's someone to see you about some plating.
好了
Okay-
- 欢迎再来 - 谢谢
- Back there. - Thank you.
我是阿泰格利亚先生
I'm Mr. Attaglia.
你没收到那批货 还是什么的 请坐
You didn't get a delivery or somethin"? Sit down.
锌 什么
Zinc? What?
我叫弗兰克
My name is Frank
那都是屁话
and that was bullshit.
- 这是什么 - "这"是乔·盖格思
- What is this? - "This" is Joe Gags.
那185000美元 是我的钱
$185,000 of my money.
就是这个问题
We have this problem.
什么问题 你在说什么呢
What problem? What are you talkin' about?
他把我的货运走了
He was moving my merchandise
所以他跑路时口袋里的钱都是我的
so the money in his pocket when he went out the window is my money.
这是电镀厂 你在跟我说什么屁话
This is a plating company. What are you telling me this shit?
"屁话" 我只要我的钱
"Shit"? I want my money.
我不知道你在说什么
Hey, I don't know what you're talkin' about...
弗兰克先生 随便吧
Mr. Frank La La... whatever.
- 有人死了 - 是的
- Some guy die? - Yes.
房产拿去遗嘱公证 拿上遗嘱去法庭 来烦我干嘛
The estate goes to probate. Take it to probate court. What do you bug me with this?
我来这给你商量一些业务
I come here to discuss a piece of business with you.
你要做什么 你要告诉我童话故事
And what are you gonna do? You gonna tell me fairy tales?
你他妈是谁啊 傻逼 有人认识你
Who the fuck are you, slick? Somebody knows you?
疯子你是来干嘛的 我不认识你
What are you, crazy? I don't know you.
也不认识什么叫盖格思的傻逼
I don't know some clown named Gags.
从这出去 卡尔
Get outta here. Carl!
快他妈从这滚出去
Go ahead, get the fuck outta here.
- 别动 - 好 好
- Hold it. - All right, all right.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
好好 照他说的做
All right, do what he says.
- 照他说的做 - 趴下
- Do what he says. - Lay down.
快
Go ahead.
手放头上 腿分开 快
Put your hands on your head. Spread your legs. Now.
嘿 你个呆逼 看墙
Hey, you, you goof! Look at the wall.
我是这世界上
I am the last guy in the world
你最不敢惹的人
that you want to fuck with.
你在盖格思那找到我的钱
You found my money on Gags.
我们先假设你不知道那是谁的钱
Let us pretend you don't know whose money it is.
是是 我不知道你是谁
That's right. I don't know who you are.
三个小时
Three hours.
我会安排一个见面
I will call to set a meet.
你要付给我185000美元
You will pay me my money. $185,000.
坐下
Sit down.
谢谢你来的这么快
Thanks for comin' on down so soon.
无论如何我都会来
I was comin' anyway.
- 过的怎么 - 我
- How's it goin'? - Me?
好得很
I am doin' terrific.
每天都是惊喜
Every day is a surprise.
这外面真他妈的奇怪
It is real fuckin' weird out there.
很多事情和我们想的不一样
It is nothing like we figured out.
那么你怎么样 老兄
So what's to it, my man?
老样子 莫里斯终于毁了雷德的普鲁酒的运作 [一种专供犯人的酒]
Same old shit. Morris finally busted Red's pruno operation.
- 更多的杀戮将要继续 - 毒品
- And a lot of knifings going on. - Yeah. Dope?
是啊 还有滚床单
Yeah, that and sex.
你简直不能相信进来这里的人的素质
You wouldn't believe the quality of people they're puttin' in here.
十年或者十五年前 他们被关到精神病院之类的地方
Ten or 15 years ago, they'd have dumped 'em in a funny farm.
那些强奸犯 还有猥亵儿童的人
Rapists, child molesters.
现在他们和大多数罪犯一样被他妈关在这
They put that shit in here with the mainstream population.
要是以前 那些人能坚持五天 简直是个奇迹
Used to be, somebody like that, if they lasted five days, it'd be a record.
现在 这不科学
Perverse.
你老婆怎么样了
How's the wife?
老婆
The wife?
老婆没有了 我离婚了
There's nothing with the wife. I pulled the plug.
发生什么了
What happened?
嗯 我
Uh, I, uh -
她不知道我在外面干这些偷鸡摸狗的事
She does not know I'm putting down scores
而且她是火箭科学家 她发现了
and the rocket scientist that she is, she figures out
我和风尘女子的风流韵事
that I am having affairs with fancy ladies.
反正现在整个人都不好了
Anyway, it gets all screwy and twisted.
那你准备做什么呢
What are you gonna do?
嗯 我准备像以前那样
Well, I'm gonna put it back together.
我遇见一个少妇 叫杰西
Look, I met this new chick, this Jessie.
- 你准备和她结婚生子了 - 是
- You gonna marry her and have kids? - Yes.
但是
But, uh
她不知道我准备做这些
she does not know what I do.
还能怎样 让我一直这样哄她骗她 还是其他什么
So what? I mean, do I bullshit her along, or what?
别骗人了
Lie to no one.
如果是与你亲近的人 谎言会毁了你们之间的关系
If they're somebody close to you, you're gonna ruin it with a lie.
要是陌生人 管你他妈骗的是谁
And if they're a stranger, who are they you gotta lie to?
嘿老兄 你需要什么
Hey, what do you need, man?
把我从这弄出去
Get me out of here.
十个月之后 你就能走在大街上
Ten months and you're on the street.
- 你认识谢尔顿博士吗 - 认识
- You know Doc Shelton? - Yeah.
这个老杂种杀了很多的人 比用电椅的还多
That old bastard's killed more guys than the electric chair.
唔 我有心绞痛之类之类的
Well, I got angina somethin' somethin' somethin'
我撑不了十个月
and I'm not gonna last ten months.
弗兰克 我不想死在这
And I don't want to die in here, Frank.
不要死在这
Not in here.
哦 没问题
Well, you got it.
去吧 孩子
Gotta go, kid.
你放心
You got it.
他说他把货留给了盖格思
He downed the merch to Gags is what he said.
我告诉你这些混蛋很麻烦 我们把他大卸八块
I'm telling you, this cocksucker's trouble. We whack him out.
是这小偷
Is this the prowler?
- 这货是盖格思 - 一定是
- The guy Gags had? - Has to be the one.
我叫里欧 你好
My name's Leo. How are ya?
我 我叫弗兰克
How am I? I am Frank.
你的钱
Here's your money.
天呐
Jesus Christ!
那有一沓的钞票
There's two inches of money out there.
- 都在这了吧 - 应该是
- Is it all there? - I am sure that it is.
- 你不说声谢谢之类的吗 - 这钱是谁的
- Don't you say thanks or somethin'? - Whose money is this?
是你的钱 不过我阻止了这家伙给你找麻烦
Your money. But I stopped this guy from giving you a hard time.
好吧 谢谢
Well, thanks.
不客气 没什么了不起的
You're welcome. It's no big deal.
我知道
I'll see ya.
- 你要去哪 - 我要去哪
- Where are you goin'? - Where am I going?
- 嗯 - 我要迟到了
- Yeah. - I am late.
别这样嘛
Come on.
我们谈点小生意
I thought we'd talk a little business
让我们互相了解一下
get to know each other.
呃 无意冒犯
Uh, no of fence.
你想要找人聊天 就加入寂寞空虚冷俱乐部吧
You want to get to meet people, join a lonely-hearts club.
我已经了解你了
I know you already.
- 是吗 - 嗯
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 你怎么了解的 - 你留给盖格思的那些货
- How you know me? - That merch you put down to Gags.
马克思·谢尔曼
Max Sherman.
那个波多黎各的黑商人 卡塔萨尔
Puerto Rican fence. Uh, Cotazar.
你觉得他们把货放在了 跟我说
Where do you think they down it? To me.
我可是黑货仓库 掌握着半个城市的黑货
I'm the bank. I handle the fence for half this city.
你一个月干两三次
You been puttin' down two, three scores a month
偷了一个月又一个月
month in, month out.
我知道你什么胃口 你尝到甜头了
I see your stuff. You got great taste.
像个外表光鲜的妓女
Regular high-line pro.
所以我跟盖格思说 "我想见见这家伙"
So I said to Gags, "I want to meet this guy."
- 他跟你说了吗 - 嗯
- He tell you that? - Yes.
- 那很好 - 我们少废话了
- Fine. - Let's cut the bullshit.
他是说
Who is he?
我他妈怎么知道
How the hell do I know?
你想在全国范围内偷东西 直接为我工作吗
You want to put down contract scores all over the country, working directly for me?
我自己当老板
I am self-employed.
自己当老板感觉很好 我可不是好员工
I am doin' fine. I don't deal with egos.
我要做自己的主 干嘛还要给你打工
I am Joe the boss of my own body, so what do I have to work for you for?
你不一定做不好嘛 我会安排好的 你能当监工
Maybe you don't. I'll lay it out. You can be the judge.
不用盯着
You don't look...
不用处理事务 不用做任何事
you don't case, you don't do nothin'.
我们找地方让你下手
We point you to a score.
我们说有就会有
When we say it's there, it's there.
都是安排好的
They're all laid-out scores.
怎么安排的
How are they worked up?
报警系统的图解 设计图 有时候还有前门钥匙
Alarm system diagrams, blueprints, sometimes a front-door key.
有时候小偷熟悉内情 每个人都想宰保险公司一顿
Sometimes the scores are in on it. Everybody's ripping off the insurance company.
- 干活的车 销账的地方 还有工具 - 你要什么尽管说
- Work cars? Drops? Tools? - Whatever you need, you'd see me.
我当你教父
I'd be your father.
钱啊 枪啊 车啊 从现在起我就是你教父了
Money, guns, cars... I'd be your father from here on out.
- 我能得到啥 - 你能分成啊 分多少可没得商量
- What's my end? - You get a price. No negotiation.
我们能得到你从没见过的那么多钱 不过我们得把分成谈好
We got expenses you don't have. But you'll know the price up front.
- 多少 - 大部分
- How big? - Boxcar.
绝不低于六位数 我让你四个月内成百万富翁
Nothin' under six figures. I'll make you a millionaire in four months.
我给你工作 就会被曝光得更多
I go to work for you, I'm pullin' a lot of exposure.
- 我的保护者会处理好的 - 好吧 我考虑一下
- Our protection trades that off. - Yeah, I take a bust.
转身 有个律师
Turn around, there's gonna be a lawyer
担保人在那 保证你不会被关牢里
a bondsman right there... you never spend a night in jail.
听着 我只偷珠宝 不偷皮草或是珍藏版的硬币
Look, I steal ice. No furs, no coin collections
股票 运送的货物 债券什么的 都不偷
no stock certificates, no cartage, no Treasury bonds, no nothin'.
- 只有钻石或者现金 - 行
- Just diamonds or cash. - Fine.
- 我不莽撞行事 也不入室抢劫 - 好好
- No cowboy shit. No home invasions. - Fine.
- 我有个同伴一起干活 - 我们只负责你
- I work with a partner. - We take care of you.
你的同伙你自己照顾 他对你发牢骚 那是你自己的问题
A partner is strictly your responsibility. He beefs on you, that's your problem.
他对我们发牢骚 也是你自己的问题
He beefs on us, that's your problem too.
- 你的人都有哪些 - 这是我的底线 你不需要知道任何事情
- Who are your inside people? - That's my end. You don't have to know anything about that.
你看怎么样 弗兰克
So what do you say?
还不清楚
I don't know.
- 不清楚 什么意思 - 就是不清楚
- What do you mean, you don't know? - I don't know!
我不相信这些终身协议
I don't believe in lifetime subscriptions.
- 可能这不符合我的退休计划 - 你退休之后要做什么
- Maybe it don't fit in with my retirement program. - What are you gonna do retired?
养养鸡 没事看看电视 有什么问题吗
Pick corn with the chickens. Watch daytime TV the rest of my life. What's the difference?
没问题 没问题
All right, all right.
很多路可以走呢
Two, three moves.
你想继续干 当然好
You want to keep goin', that's fine.
你要收手 也没问题
But if you wanna split, that's fine too.
买卖不成仁义在 大家都是大人了
Everybody's business-like. Everybody's an adult.
做个决定吧
So let me know
我们会做大做强的
'cause we'd be terrific.
嗯 那好吧 我会打电话给你
Yeah, that's fine. I'll call ya.
- 你要接纳他吗 - 再说吧
- You wanna pick him up? - We'll see.
♪ Sho lover ♪
♪ Sweet thing♪
♪ I reached a turning point♪
♪ In my life♪
♪ I reached a turning point Lord, Lord, Lord♪
♪ I met a girl♪
♪ She's one out of 110♪
♪ And she don't get excited No, no, no♪
♪ By no slick-talkin' men♪
♪ She's a wiz around the house♪
♪ Neat as a pin♪
♪ If I got a hole in my socks got a hole in my shirt♪
♪ Sweet thing, she'll mend♪
♪ No more stayin' out late for me♪
♪ No more narrow escapes♪
♪ I reached a turning point♪
♪ Turning point♪
♪ In my life♪
♪ I reached a turning point Lord, Lord, Lord♪
♪ In my life ♪
♪ Come on, let's groove it one time. ♪
♪ No more runnin' around for me♪
♪ Finally settlin' down♪
♪ I reached a turning point Lord, Lord♪
♪ In my life♪
♪ I reached a turning point Lord, Lord, Lord♪
♪ And I don't know where I would end up♪
♪ If that sweet thing hadn't come along♪
♪ If that sweet thing hadn't come along ♪
- 快点 我的车在非停车路段停着呢 - 你这该死的 来这干嘛
- Hurry. I got my car parked in red. - What the hell are you doing here?
- 来找你 - 别碰我行吗
- Finding you. - Get away from me, okay?
你迟到两小时了 不用你来找我
You are two hours late. I do not need this.
我不要你来出我的丑
I do not need to be humiliated.
- 等等 我想和你谈谈 - 不谈
- Wait. I want to talk to you. - No.
你
Hey, you!
带你去咖啡厅 再解释给你听。多大点事儿
I will take you for coffee and explain. What's the big God damn deal?
你带我去 真是笑话
You, take me anywhere? That's a big laugh.
是有原因的 我正要跟你说呢
- Look, maybe there is a reason. - Hey, I'm talkin' to you.
嘿 你这家伙 走开行吗 滚
Hey! Take a walk, flash. All right? Go on.
嘿 小心点宝贝
Hey, watch out, baby!
我不知道你是因为什么原因 也不想知道
I don't know the reason. I don't want to hear the reason.
没有原因 就这样
There is no reason. That's all.
多大点事儿 听着 你会期待这个的
What's the big God damn... Look, you were lookin' forward to this.
来
Come on.
- 上车 达令 - 不要
- Get in the car, darling. - No!
等一下
Wait a minute!
- 嘿 - 我的天
- Hey! - My God!
哦 这人
Oh, man!
- 我干了什么 - 你干嘛推他
- What did I do? - Why did you push him?
听着 我做的事情都充满压力
Look, in what I do, there are sometimes pressures.
你觉得我究竟是做什么的
What the hell do you think that I do?
说啊
Come on, come on!
快说 这五个月的每个早晨我都出来散步 和你打招呼
Come on! Every morning I walk in for five months, say hi.
你觉得我究竟是做什么的
What the hell do you think that I do?
你卖他妈的小汽车 就是做这个的
You sell little fuckin' cars, that's what you do.
我穿着150块的休闲裤和丝绸衬衫
I wear $150 slacks! I wear silk shirts!
我穿着800块的西装 戴着金表
I wear $800 suits! I wear a gold watch!
我戴着最上品的钻戒 三克拉
I wear a perfect D flawless, three-carat ring!
我像别的家伙一样 卖汽车还有卖他妈的鞋
I change cars like other guys change their fuckin' shoes!
我是个小偷 坐过牢
I'm a thief. I've been in prison.
- 那又怎样 我不在意 - “那又怎样 ”
- So what'? I don't care. - "So what"?
- 别告诉我 - 我从没跟你提过我老婆
- Don't tell me... - I never even told my wife that!
- 我不在乎 - 她现在离开了
- I don't care! - Who is now gone.
- 我轻薄你了吗 - 没有
- Did I ever come on to you? - No.
- 好了 你看吧 - 看 看什么
- Well, you see? - See? See what?
看 我是个老实人
See... I am a straight arrow.
我是个忠实善良的人
I am a true-blue kind of a guy.
我冷静过 我现在孤身一人
I've been cool. I am now unmarried.
让我们直截了当 少说废话
So let's cut the mini-moves and the bullshit
就这样浪漫相处
and get on with this big romance.
什么
What?
我才不相信
I don't believe it!
你知道不知道我一直都在等你来
Do you think I have been waiting for you to come along?
这他妈是演哪一出
What is this shit?
你觉得我在说笑 那我明确告诉你 我是认真的
You think I'm kiddin'. I can tell. This is strictly on the up-and-up.
老天爷
Jesus Christ!
- 你怕死 - 你个混蛋
- You are scared to death. - You're an asshole.
那也是可爱的混蛋
That's lovely.
生活这么美好 你要干嘛
What are you doing in your life that is so terrific?
- 我活得好得很 - 那是 坐这
- My life is fine. - Yeah, sure. Here.
- 你不了解我 - 是吗
- You don't know about me. - Yeah?
- 我什么都知道 - 你知道个屁
- I know all about- - You know bullshit.
嘿
HEY-
你干嘛大喊大叫
Why you gotta shout?
麻烦给我两杯咖啡
Excuse me. Can we have two coffees here?
不好意思 继续吧
Sorry. So?
"继续" 继续干嘛
"So"? So what?
继续告诉我
So tell me.
需要菜单吗
Menus?
不用 谢谢
No, thanks.
那么 你以前的生活是什么样的
So, uh, what was it like?
你知道的 有很多钱 到图森[ 亚利桑那州南部城市]
You know, a lot of money. Tucson,
墨西哥 波哥大[哥伦比亚首都]
Mexico City, Bogota'.
漂泊 你知道的吧
Drifting, you know. Okay?
嗯
Okay.
曾经的生活让人纠结 让人讨厌 让人感到空虚
It got twisted and ugly and empty.
它已经过去了 可我们一直保持着那份感动
It was over already, but we kept moving through the moves.
它非常糟糕地结束了
It ended very badly.
现在每天早晨起来 洗个澡
Now I get up in the morning, I take a shower
去上班 我有工作 有社保
I go to work, I have a job, I have a Social Security card.
我的生活非常普通 太无聊了
And my life is very ordinary, very boring
是不差 因为太死板了
which is good, because it's solid.
你这就是在原地踏步
You're marking time is what you are.
你放弃了 退缩了
You're backing off. You're hiding out.
你在等一辆你希望它永远都不来的巴士
You're waiting for a bus you hope never comes
因为你不想上车 哪都不想去
because you don't want to get on it anyway because you don't wanna go anywhere.
你有资格上这辆巴士吗
Do you have a licence for this?
好吧 他让你有多感动
All right, how much was he moving?
直到结束都没有什么感动
Nothing, till the end.
或许有很多 我 我也不知道
And then kilo amounts. I don't... I don't know.
然后呢
And then what?
- 他死了 - 嗯
- He's dead. - Hmm?
他死了
He is dead.
这很好 因为他是个混蛋
That is good, because he's an asshole.
- 一开始感情很深 - 那家伙就是个混蛋
- There was a lot of love in the beginning. - The guy was an asshole.
- 最初是有感情的 - 大混蛋
- There was love in the beginning. - A big asshole.
他把你关起来 在哥伦比亚 你难道不知道
He put you in a box. You know the things they do to you
他们让你一天接十次客
ten times a day if you do a bit in Colombia?
- 难道不记得吗 天呐 - 别在这吵
- Do you? Jesus Christ! - Don't shout in here.
我那时独自一个人
I was alone.
没钱没衣服 没信用卡
I had no money, no clothes, no visa...
就生活在哥伦比亚波哥大的角落
standing on the corner in Bogota' in Colombia.
然后这些事就发生了
Things did happen.
你在哪蹲监狱 能把奶油递给我吗
Where were you in prison? Would you pass the cream, please?
乔利矣特监狱
Joliet.
那的典狱长 哦 天
The warden... Whoa, God!
嘿 能再给我们一些奶油吗
Hey, can we have some new cream here?
怎么了
What's wrong with it?
"怎么了" 这是脱脂炼乳
"What's wrong with it?" It's cottage cheese.
那的典狱长是乔·里根
The warden there was, uh, Joe Reagan.
外号"傻蛋乔"
"Meatball Joe."
如果那傻逼是个学典狱学的 那我就是飞行员了
If that slob was a penologist, I'm a jet aeroplane pilot.
我蹲了十一年
I did eleven years.
出来四年了
I got out, what, four years ago.
因为什么被关进去的
What'd you go up for?
偷了四十块钱
I stole forty dollars.
四十块钱
Forty dollars?
嗯
Yeah.
本来缓刑两年 六个月内能假释
Started with a two-year bit, parole in six months.
可是后来
And then right away
我和另外两个家伙闹矛盾
I got into this problem with these two guys.
他们想把我赶出去
They tried to turn me out.
所以 我申诉了很多很多次
So I picked up nine more
说他们有杀人倾向
on a manslaughter beef
还有其他一些事
some other things.
进去的时候才二十岁 出来的时候就三十一了
I was 20 when I went in, 31 when I come out.
你对时间没概念
You don't count months and years.
你没坐过牢
You don't do time that way.
为何你要这样说
What do you mean? Why?
为何 你都忘了时间
Why? You gotta forget time.
你都不关心你是死是活
You gotta not give a fuck if you live or die.
你也不在意要去哪里
You gotta get to where nothin' means nothin'.
我会告诉你这一切
I'll tell you a story all about it.
又一次 有个三百磅的笨蛋
Once there was this Captain Morphis...
孟菲斯长官 他不会写他的名字
this 300-pound slob. He couldn't write his name.
他有一群
And he had this crew
十六七岁的警卫和手下
of 16 or 17 guards and cons.
典狱团队 你知道吧 就那一群人
Prison groups, you know? Crews.
他们到牢房里
They would go into these cells
带走一些小伙子
and grab these young guys
带他们去精神病房进行水疗
and bring 'em up to hydrotherapy in the mental ward.
呃 其实是轮奸
Uh, gang bang.
要是有人敢反抗 他们就把他打个半死
If a guy puts up a struggle, they beat him half to death
然后被送去精神病院
and he winds up in the funny farm.
无论怎样 噩耗来袭 我是下一个
Anyway, word comes down that I am next
我不知道该怎么办才好
and I do not know what I am supposed to do.
我 我很害怕
I, uh... I am scared.
十一点半 十二点 亮灯了
11:30, 12:00, lights come on.
我抓了一个铅管
I got this pipe from plumbing
然后
and, uh
狠狠地打在第一个守卫的小腿上
I whacked the first guard in the shins.
我就犯罪了 算另一项罪行
I go through a convict and another convict and...
不管这么多 我找到孟菲斯 上去就朝他头抡了两下
Anyway, I get to Morphis, and I whack him across the head twice.
砰 他们都朝我扑来 一顿毒打
Boom. And then they jump all over me, do a bunch of things.
我在医院病房里躺了六个月 但是
I spent six months in the hospital ward, but
孟菲斯也他妈没好到哪去
Morphis, he is also fucked up real good.
脑血肿
Cerebral haematoma.
得到了抚恤金 他都不能正常走路
They pension him out, he can't walk straight
两年后他就死了
and he dies two years later
真是这世界的一大损失
which is a real loss to the planet Earth.
这时候我也回到
Meanwhile, I gotta go back
大多数罪犯关的那里
into the mainstream population
在我进去的时候 我就知道自己是个要死的人了
and I know the minute I hit the yard, I am a dead man.
所以我就进去了
So I hit the yard.
然后 你知道发生了什么吗
So you know what happens?
没什么 我是说什么都没发生
Nothin'. I mean, nothin' happens.
因为我觉得自己活着没什么意思 我都不在乎了
'Cause I don't mean nothin' to myself. I don't care about me.
对什么事都漠不关心了 你知道吗
I don't care about... nothin', you know?
从我幸存下来的那天起我就这样了
And then I know from that day that I survive
我就这心态
because I achieved that mental attitude.
然后
Then, uh
然后 我
see, later, I...
我就干了这个
I worked this out.
在石头牢房里
In the stone cell.
这是什么
What is this?
这就是我的生活
That is my life.
然后
And, uh
没有什么能阻止我让这一切发生
nothin', nobody can stop me from makin' that happen.
这是现在 有你在
And right there, that would be you.
这 这个老头是谁
Who... Who's the old man here?
是大卫·奥克拉·贝尔蒂诺
That is David Okla Bertinneau.
他是小偷的祖师爷 是个大师
He's a master thief... a master...
也是个很好的人
and a great man.
他像爸爸一样 教会我很多
He was like a father. He taught me everything
做人的道理
that I know about what I do.
而且我跟他说了你的事情
And I told him about you.
你是从杂志还是什么剪下这些东西的
Did you cut these out from magazines and...
嗯 报纸 还有很多
Yeah. Newspapers, whatever.
为什么
Why...
为什么是这些该死的人
Why all of these dead people?
从内心来看 你一直都被关在监狱里
Inside, you are on ice from time.
甚至都不能死去 知道吗 而外面的世界
You can't even die right, you know? And here...
成长
here, people grow.
老去
They get old, they die.
新生
Children come after.
就是个循环 对吧
Just a cycle, you know?
我不懂 我
I don't know. I...
不 你会明白的
Yes, you do. You do.
你知不知道这日升月落
You don't know from one day to the next
与你是否被杀 是否回家 是否被抓 都没有关系
whether you're going to be killed, go home, or get busted.
听着 时光流尽
Look, I have run out of time.
我会失去这一切
I have lost it all.
我工作得不够努力 跑得不够快
And so I can't work fast enough to catch up
难以追回逝去的光阴
and I can't run fast enough to catch up
也只有使用我的魔法
and the only thing that catches me up
才能让我追赶上
is doin' my magic act.
但是这结束了 你知道吗 它要结束了
But it ends, you know? It will end.
当我拿到这东西的时候
When I got this, right there
就结束了
it ends, it's over.
所以我就是想请求你
So I'm just asking you
和我在一起吧
to be with me.
不行
I can't.
I can't, uh...
我不能生孩子
I can't have children.
我不习惯这样
I don't fit into this.
为什么 那我们慢慢习惯
What? So we adopt.
我 我还没准备好 行吗
I... I'm not ready, see?
而且我有我的生活
And... And I have my life.
- 所以 不行 - 什么
- So I... I can't. - What?
我是说 你的美好生活会变成怎样
I mean, what is going on in your life that is so terrific?
我的已经是一团糟了
Mine's been a mess.
我只是想 你知道的
I was just thinkin', you know, that
我们之间可能
just maybe between the two of us
我们可以有很多故事
we could make somethin' happen
一些特别的 美好的故事
somethin' special, somethin' really nice.
知道吗
You know?
所以我只是 我只是问问你
So I'm just, uh... I'm just askin' you
嗯
uh, to, uh...
听着 我知道一种让美好生活更快实现的方法
Look, I got a way now I can make it happen faster.
我是说 快很多
I mean, much faster.
我只是
And, uh, I'm just...
我只是问问你 你知道吗
I'm just askin' you, you know?
你在了 他们准备大干一场
You're on. They gotta be big scores.
他们快得很 就在眼前了
They gotta be fast. One, two tops.
好
Right.
- 就是那 - 哪
- That's it. - Where?
从上往下数第三层 这边
Third from the top, this side.
- 警报系统呢 - 五个独立的系统
- Alarm systems? - Five independent systems.
四个静默报警器通过电话接入警报公司
Four silent ringers into an alarm company over the phone lines.
还有红外检测
Infra-red pots
前门有磁铁 连着声音报警器
magnetics on the front door, sonic alarm.
- 保险库装了防盗报警器 - 这是什么
- Vault door's bugged. - What's this?
这是顶楼 电梯井的顶层
This is the top floor. Top of the elevator shafts.
八楼有十四根报警电话线缆
Floors eight through 14's alarm lines conduit with the phones
通到电梯井顶层
through the top of the elevator shaft.
坐电梯到顶楼
What about taking the elevator to the top floor
打开舱门 去找电话线 这样怎么样
open the hatch, and goin' in that way?
不行 晚上的时候电梯会被锁上 防盗报警器会被打开
No. Elevators are locked down and bugged at night.
只要有两套系统 你那方法就不行了
Your way, I gotta take out two systems.
把屋顶搞穿 找到那些线
Chop through the roof and get the lines that way.
假设我们通过了报警系统 那保险柜是什么样的
Assuming we get the alarm, what is the box?
列治文·莱科特牌的
Richmond-Lackett.
- 列治文·莱科特牌 - 嗯
- Richmond-Lackett? - Yeah.
太好了 那玩意坚若磐石
Terrific. It's a burn job.
- 没法钻开 - "钻"
- No way to drill? - "Drill"?
- 嗯 - 钻什么
- Yeah. - Drill what?
那些可是定制版的 你把那保险柜敲一整天 它都安然无恙
They're custom-made. You bang on this box all day, nothin' happens.
而且这太冒险了
And I am pulling a lot of exposure.
让我在那呆十六 十八个小时
Sixteen, eighteen hours in there.
你承担风险 给你八十三万
Your end covers the risk. $830,000.
把这些没切割的钻石全卖了有四百万
Four million at wholesale in unmounted stones.
- 第五层警报系统是什么 - 我们还没法搞清楚
- What's the fifth alarm? - We cannot run it down.
为什么
Why?
因为它没通过电话线连出去
Because it does not go out over the phone lines.
我们查看了整栋楼的线缆
We swept the lines in the whole building.
但是我们知道它在哪 要准备多久
But we know it is there. How long?
四个 八个星期
Four, eight weeks
假设我们通过了报警系统
assuming we get the alarm
也知道怎么切开保险柜
and what to cut the box with.
我需要两个加州的通行证 还有两辆工作车
I need a couple Cal licences, and two new work cars here.
- 行 我会安排好 我们几点的飞机 - 两点半的
- Okay. I'll set it up. What time's our plane? - We're on the 2:30.
呆在这 把第五层报警系统搞定
Stay here and make out that fifth alarm.
喜欢这吗
You like it?
我是说
I mean
你觉得这还行吧
do you think it'll do or what? It's okay?
弗兰克 我喜欢这 我觉得这太棒了
Frank, I love it. I love it. I think it's terrific.
你在看什么呢
What are you looking at?
看你呢 就是看看你
You, that's all.
山姆
Sam.
过得怎么样
How you doin"?
我 我顺利的很 现在熟练了 经常得手
Me, I'm golden, glowin', scorin' like a champ.
我需要帮忙
I need a favour.
奥克拉怎么样了
How's Okla?
他得了心绞痛 我要想办法把他从那救出来
Angina. I'm makin' some moves to get him out of there.
我安排了一个听证会
I got a hearing fixed up.
那个穿着白大褂的怪人是谁
Who's the yo-yo in the white coat?
冶金学家 女婿找来的
Metallurgist. Son-in-law's idea.
一种承重管开始流行了
A load of tubing comes in
我反复研究它
I taste it, I smell it
一直在研究它
I chew it, I spit on it.
嘿 混蛋科学家
Hey, scientist cocksucker!
18%的锌 43%的铜
18% zinc, 43% copper
38%的锡 另外百分之一我也不知道
38% tin, and 1% I don't know.
白大褂 在这他穿着白大褂
A white coat. Around here he wears a white coat.
他算老几 发现了青霉素
What's he? Gonna discover penicillin?
他在这就是个穿着白大褂的笨蛋
You gotta be a real putz to wear a white coat around here.
休伊 让我们单独呆一会
Huey, excuse us.
- 什么样的钢 - 瑞典247冷轧钢
- What kind of steel? - Swedish cold-rolled, 247.
这 这 这 还有这里
Here, here, here, and here.
- 一寸厚 - 这还有铜包裹着的
- One-inch plates. - Copper to bind drills
钛合金
titanium alloy here.
做工非常好 非常贵
This is a well-made, very expensive
尤其是非常安全
very special vault.
- 英国的 - 嗯
- English? - Mm.
列治文·莱科特牌
Richmond and Lackett?
我需要一些特殊的设备
I need a very special piece of equipment.
- 在密码箱上钻个洞 - 不行 每个柜子都设计的不一样
- Drill a hole in the lock-box - - No. Each one is made different.
没法知道密码箱在哪个位置
There's no way of telling where the lock-box is.
我想切出一个门 再进去
I want to cut me a whole new door and walk in.
七八千度的温度
Seven, eight thousand degrees?
用便携式设备
Portable equipment?
- 没其他方法完成吗 - 没有
- There's no other way to do it? - No.
孩子 要是我能造出这样的设备
Sonny, if I can build something
一定是给疯子用的
it's gonna be a son of a bitch to use.
好吧 这样做值得吗
Okay, so is it worth it?
值得
It is worth it.
- 检查过电话吗 - 每个星期都检查 放心用
- You sweep the phone? - Weekly. It's clean.
你好 我是弗兰克
Hello? I'm Frank.
里欧说谈论一下加州通行证的事情
Leo said to call about California licences and registrations.
是
Yeah.
一小时内我就到126号区 我穿着灰色皮衣
I'll be in Division 126 in an hour. I'm wearing a grey leather coat.
好
Good.
怎么样 山姆
So what's to it, Sam?
我把这保险柜做一部分出来再说
I gotta build a section of vault to tell.
所以我还不知道是否有可能造个工具把它切开
So I don't know if it's even possible to build a tool that'll cut it like that.
一个星期之后来找我
See me in a week.
根据申诉权 大卫·奥克拉·贝尔蒂诺请求法官大人
The nature of this petition is that David Okla Bertinneau pleads for Your Honour
更改关于他在1958年被定罪的判决
to modify the instruction of his 1958 conviction
并且发布人身保护令
and to issue a writ of habeas corpus.
但是他违反了第三十八章第十九条的规定 入室行窃
But he violated Chapter 38, Section 19-1: burglary
第三十八章第十六条 偷窃
Chapter 38, Section 16-1: theft...
这有两张加州的通行证 我在萨克拉门托办的 [加州首府]
Here's two California licences I fixed in Sacramento.
还有国家尊严
...and dignity of the state.
很遗憾 法官大人
That distresses me, Your Honour
因为这个人已经痛改前非了
'cause this man is of reformed character
上了年纪 又患有严重的心脏病
advanced age, and suffers from a severe heart condition
可能无法继续服刑
and may not be able to serve out his sentence.
他被监禁了21年
He's spent over 21 years of incarceration
已经变成一个不同的人了
and has become a different person.
我不知道
I don't know.
我仍然表示怀疑
I remain unconvinced.
- 他们在挖鼻孔 - 等等 我想听一下
- Are they pickin' their noses? - Wait. I want to hear this.
然而 出于一些考虑
However, upon consideration
我将发布一份人身保护令
I will issue a writ of habeas corpus.
谢谢你 法官大人 我会记住您的恩泽
Thank you, Your Honour. I'll write up the order.
我知道您公事繁多 日理万机
I know how busy your docket is.
我老婆在商店买皮大衣
My wife's in the market for a fur coat.
我是个卖小轿车的
I am a car salesman.
好吧 随便你说什么么
Sure. Whatever you say.
好吧
That's right.
一个星期后 奥克拉就能出来了
Okla will be on the street in a week.
我需要六千块钱给这个法官
I need $6,000 for Earl Warren.
一个星期 嗯 给 一万块钱
A week? Yeah? Here. Ten thousand.
你这家伙还不错 给自己买套新衣服吧
You're a prince. Buy yourself a new suit.
- 一星期 - 嗯 一星期
- A week? - A week.
好极了
All right.
谁住这
Who lives here?
- 快说吧 谁住这 - 嗨
- Come on, who lives here? - Hi.
他要变成百万富翁 嗯
It's gotta be some millionaire guy, huh?
嘿 看看这些 树 花丛
Hey, look at this. Tree. Bush.
- 桃树 - 哈喽
- Pink tree. - Hello!
- 嗨! - 桃树
- Hi! - Pink?
- 嘿 这儿真棒 - 当然 进来吧
- Hey. It's real nice. - Sure. Come in back.
- 嗨 弗兰克 - 你好 玛丽
- Hi, Frank. - How you doin', Marie?
- 伙计 这很漂亮啊 - 你什么时候回来的
- This is beautiful, man. - When did you get back?
哦 昨天晚上 晚些时候
Oh, uh, last night, late.
你 你搞定第五层报警系统了
You, uh - you make that fifth alarm?
搞定了
I made the fifth alarm.
赞
Good.
- 那么 要怎么做 - 嗯
- So, uh, what's to it? - Okay.
第五层报警系统是一个单通道的无线电发射机
Alarm system number five is a one-channel radio transmitter.
- 它怎么被触发 - 在天花板上有个声音探测器
- How's it triggered? - There's a sonic detector off the ceiling.
每天早晨当他们走过 都会引起警报 "嘀铃铃" 警报被触发了
They set off the alarm every morning when they walk in. Ring, ring, ring. It's tripped.
他们有十秒钟给警报公司发送一个密码来取消报警
They have ten seconds to transmit a code word to the alarm company to cancel it.
现在 这个密码用无线电传播
Now, the code word goes over the radio.
这就是为什么没有电话线缆
That's why there's no phone lines.
好吧 让我来告诉你
All right, I tell you what.
- 你要监听密码 - 嗯
- You bug it. - All right.
打电话给约瑟夫 让他帮你按一个窃听器 然后从那回来
Call Joseph, have him fix you one, go back out there
你就监听密码
and you bug 'em for the word.
加油 这非常赞
Come on. It's gettin' cold.
嗯
Oh. Uh
这次行动 你知道的
this L.A. move, you know...
做完这一票 这房子就归我了
it's home free for me after it's done.
高兴吗
You happy?
来这
Come on.
弗兰克 想吃什么
Frank, want something to eat?
呃
Well...
我看了你的申请
I see on your application here...
顺便说一下 你把"男士"这个单词拼错了
By the way, you misspelled "male".
是M-A-L-E
It's M-A-L-E.
然后要做的就是投进邮箱
The other is what we put in postboxes.
我看你写的是"雇主"
I see you put under "employer"
"乔利矣特州立监狱 在1959到1976年间"
"1959 to 1976, Joliet State Penitentiary."
- 是的 - 你给国家工作 我说的对吗
- Yes. - You worked for the state, I take it?
- 勉强对吧 - 你在监狱里做什么工作
- After a fashion. - What did you do at the prison?
文书
Desks.
desk有文书和桌子两重意思
文书怎么会拼错单词呢 所以杰西提示了一下
我 焊桌子的
I, uh, spot-welded desks
后来我去推销鞋子
and then I got promoted to shoes.
你曾经是店面的主管吗
You were in charge of the shop?
哦 女士 我曾经是个罪犯 坐过牢
Lady, I was a convict. I was doing time.
- 你是什么 - 弗兰克 我们走
- You were what? - Frank, let's go.
你必须明白
Uh, you have to understand
我们要处理的申请比需要领养的孩子还多
we have more applicants than children.
那你们为什么还要留这些孩子在这
Then why do you still have kids here?
我要是个孩子 我可不会对这种地方着迷
As a kid, I would not be falling all over myself to stay in one of these places.
我是想减轻你们的负担
We will relieve you of some of the burden.
重点是 我们要为领养设立标准
The point is, we establish criteria for parenting
而且一个有前科的人与其他令人满意的对象相比
and an ex-convict compared to other desirables...
等等 所以是 我们想领养 你们对我不满意
Wait. So we'll take a kid that's not so desirable.
你有黑人孩子吗 我就要黑人孩子
You got a black kid? We'll take a black kid.
- 你有裂唇的孩子 - 你不明白
- You got a Chink kid? - You don't understand...
没人喜欢大孩子 你有成年的裂唇的黑人孩子吗 我们要了
No one likes older kids. You got an 8-year-old black Chink kid? We'll take him.
- 弗兰克 - 如果是这个的问题 你知道的
- Fran... - If it's a matter of, you know... here.
- 这是什么 - "这是什么"
- What is that? - "What is that"?
最上级 3.2克拉 祖母绿
That is D flawless, 3.2 carats, emerald-cut.
- 这里可不是交易市场 - 对
- This is not a marketplace. - Right.
做这事你不够聪明 因为你认不出什么是好父母
You're not smart enough to take this any more than you are to recognize good parents.
从我办公室出去
Get out of my office.
你不用问我们是什么样的人
You did not ask about us, what kind of people we are.
有孩子在等待 你却拒绝了他 也拒绝了我们
There is a child waiting, and you are denying us him and him us.
- 你算什么东西 - 不要吵架
- Who the hell are you? - Don't make a scene.
- 我们有标准 - 你们的标准
- Our criteria... - Your criteria?
你们的标准就是把你们自己捧得高高的 而那些孩子却看不到希望 都是放屁
Your criteria are so far up your ass, they can't see daylight. This is bullshit!
算了 我们走吧
Look, it's not happening. Let's go.
女士 我教你一些基础知识
I got some ABC-type information for you, lady.
我是坐过牢的人
I was state-raised
监狱真是个该死的地方
and this is a dead place.
一个孩子在八乘四大小的牢房里
A child in eight-by-four green walls...
过了一会你对墙说 "我的生命是你的"
after a while you tell the walls, "My life is yours."
- 你在郊区长大 - 是
- You grow up in the suburbs? - Yes.
好 好
Right. Right.
看什么呢你 嗯
What are you lookin' at? Huh?
杰米好多了
Jimmy's got better.
嗯 那是因为他把他们训了一顿
Yeah, it's 'cause he charcoals them... charcoals.
- 我去把他接过了 - 好
- I'm gonna pull him over here. - Yeah.
嘿 你好
Hey, how you doin'?
- 我好得很 谢谢 - 嗯 好样的
- I'm wonderful, thank you. - Yeah, that's good.
你知道 对来说有件非常重要的事情要记住
You know, a very important thing for you to remember
就是我的名字 萨金特·尤瑞兹
is gonna be my name: Sergeant Urizzi.
尤瑞兹 为什么要记住这个
Urizzi. Why's that?
因为我要给你些好东西
Because I'm gonna do good things for ya.
给什么 品德优良奖章
What for? Good-conduct medal?
不
Nah.
我让你生活得更轻松
I'm here to make life easy for you.
- 哦 是吗 - 消除障碍和烦恼
- Oh, yeah? - Smooth out the bumps and the humps.
你知道 我们之间这关系
You know... your relationship with us.
我不知道 我有个伙伴了
I didn't know I had one.
我们是你的新伙伴 我们的加入对你有帮助
Look, we're your new partners. We're in for ten points.
是什么让你把时间推迟了
What'd this set you back?
对什么有帮助
Ten points of what?
你知道的
You know.
那家伙 里欧
The guy? Leo.
你的行动
Your action.
我不明白 你和谁一起
I don't get this. What's with you?
听着
Listen.
我们的目的
Our end
是为了迎合你们的需求
goes with the territory.
难道你不知道要发生什么
Don't you know you gotta come up?
我是个卖小轿车的
I am a car salesman.
你这家伙要是想买别克 那就上来
You guys want a deal on a Buick, come on.
- 嘿 你他妈的 - 等等
- Hey, motherfucker... - Wait, wait.
别靠近我 还有你
Don't you come on to me. And you...
你想勒索我 那我就出去跟你单挑
You want to pinch me, pinch me. I'll be out in ten minutes.
如果不是 那他妈离我车远一点
If not, get the fuck off my car!
你还好吗
You all right?
什么意思
What does this mean?
我是说
It means
警探 警察
heat, police.
意思是对我来说很难改变现在的状况
Means it's hard for me to make moves from now on.
车里的传呼机都也被监听了
Beepers on the cars, the works.
他们在墙里吗 能听到我们说的每一句话
Are they in the walls? Can they hear everything we say all the time?
可能只是用电话监听 但是我检查了
Probably it's just the phones, but I'll check.
你一点都不轻松
You're uneasy.
去他妈的房子 我们搬走吧
Fuck this house. We move.
我很好 很好
I'm okay. I'm okay.
杂种
Bastards.
嘿 乔斯·科瑞克 坐吧
Hey, José Greco, sit down.
我从你那的洛杉矶商店搞到一笔生意
I got this business deal from your end of the L.A. score.
要不要分给你一些
Want me to put some of it to work for you?
- 卖混合果汁 - "果汁" 你可不能让我从床上起来就为了这东西
- Street juice? - You couldn't get me out of bed for that.
我们可不要这些便宜货
We're not cuttin' up nickels here.
购物中心
Shopping centres.
沃斯堡市 达文波特市 杰克逊市
Fort Worth, Davenport, Jackson.
绝对合法
Strictly legit.
- 我的钱要进我的口袋 - 只要你想要 都是你的
- My money goes in my pocket. - Yours if you want in.
给你所需要的任何东西
Gonna give you everything you need.
也不一定要现在告诉我 晚点说也行
You don't have to tell me now. Let me know later.
告诉你 我想知道的是
Let you know? What I want to know is...
为什么自从我跟你合伙之后 每个人都知道我的事情
why the minute I get locked up with you, everybody knows my business.
我家被监听了 我妻子心烦
My house is bugged. My wife is upset.
车管局的那家伙想要一件毛皮大衣
The guy at the Vehicle Bureau wants a fur coat.
半个街区就有警察的踪迹 我的车也被监视了
There's a cop tail half a block down the street. My car is bugged.
看 我找到一个在保险杠上
Here. This one behind the bumper I'm supposed to find.
另一个在车轮上 当我是傻子呢 这他妈是什么玩意
The other one in the wheel well is supposed to fool me. What the hell is this?
- 交给我吧 - 交给你什么 快去做
- Leave it to me. - Leave what to you? Do it!
我说了包在我身上
I said I'll take care of it.
- 保险柜搞定得怎么样了 - 什么怎么样
- What about burning the vault? - What about it?
- 能搞定吗 - 我不知道
- Can you do it? - I don't know.
好吧 第五层警报系统呢
Okay. Fifth alarm system?
现在还没有结果
Nothing yet.
好
Okay.
除此之外你还在想什么
What else you got on your mind?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你有内顾之忧 为那个老女人的事情
You got family troubles? Somethin' with the old lady?
- 老女人是谁 人见人爱的婊子 - 你想领养个孩子
- What is this, Dear fuckin' Abby? - You tryin' to adopt a kid?
你怎么知道的
How you know that?
巴里跟米奇说 米奇又告诉我
Barry mentioned to Mitch, Mitch to me.
你有朋友 看在上帝的份上 听着
You got friends. Lighten up, for Christ sake.
为什么不跟我说你的难处
Why don't you come to me with your problems?
我是算什么 算个陌生人
What am I, a fuckin' stranger?
我会照顾我好的兄弟 给你任何想要的
I take care of my people. Anything you want.
你和我 我们合伙 我不会把事情搞复杂
You and me, we do business. I do not mix apples and oranges.
- 哦 屁话 - "屁话"
- Yeah, bullshit. - "Bullshit"?
嗯 屁话
Yeah.
和我的妻儿在一起
With my wife, with my kids...
就是我生活的全部
that's my whole life.
我们非常亲密 孩子是个特别的 奇迹
We are very tight. Kids are special, a miracle.
小男子汉 充满阳光
A little hoochie-coo, drop of energy
简单 美好
wham, barn, magic Sam...
这一切是那么的神圣
there's something sacred there.
这就是我的态度
That's my attitude.
然后呢
What happens?
说说你想要什么样的
You state your model.
黑皮肤 棕皮肤 黄皮肤 还是白的
Black, brown, yellow or white.
男孩还是女孩
Boy or girl.
从哪来
Where from?
别的夫妻生的
Couple of ladies.
他们有了孩子就拿来卖
They got babies to sell.
- 他们自己生的 再卖掉 - 天呐
- Their own. They sell 'em. - Jesus!
这不是孩子的错 他妈妈是个混蛋
It's not the kid's fault his mother's an asshole.
不然的话 你要是不买个妈妈 就没法正常地得到个小孩
And you're not buyin' the mother. You're not gonna get a kid on the straight.
我想要个男孩
I want a boy.
- 好 - 嗯
- Done. - Hmm?
好了 你会有男孩
Done. You got a boy.
- 是吗 - 嗯 - 我会有个男孩
Yeah? I got a boy?
嗯 还想要其他什么
Yeah. What else you want?
- 你个贱人 - 嘿 米奇 别
- You son of a bitch! - Hey, Mitch, get the...
是啊! 你要有个男孩了 快滚吧
Yeah! You got a boy. Get outta here.
给我电话用一下
Gimme a phone, willya?
好
Right.
嘿 杰斯
Hey, Jess.
不算差 没事
It's okay. Go ahead.
嘿 伙计
Hey, pal.
你在干嘛 在这装死
What are you doin'? You playin' sick in here?
我给你找了三个雏儿在外面等你呢
I got three chicks waitin' for you on the street.
你这不是让我难堪吗
You're gonna get me in trouble.
蠢货
Goof.
哦 这是我妻子 杰西
Oh, this is my wife, Jessie.
弗兰克
Frank.
紧急警报 你必须离开
Code blue. You'll have to leave.
- 不不 - 你必须离开
- No. - You'll have to leave.
弗兰克 走吧
Frank, come on.
在听到
After the hearing
拉姆齐法官给予他的释放令之后
Judge Ramsey's court writ him mittimus papers.
委员会必须把他交给我
The board had to release him to me.
在外面的楼梯上
On the stairs outside
他摔倒了
he just dropped.
他对你说了什么悄悄话
What did he whisper to you?
他说 你知道的 他说谢谢
He said, uh... he said thanks, you know
把他救出来
for gettin' him out.
这是重要的事 你知道的
That's the big thing, you know -
不要死在牢里 不要死在那
not to die in that joint, not to die in there.
这很重要
It's a big thing.
- 谁是贝尔蒂诺先生的家人 - 我是
- Who's Mr. Bertinneau's family? - I am.
我很抱歉 他挺不过来了
Look, I'm sorry he didn't make it.
如果有任何我能做的
If there's anything I can do, uh...
- 你还好吗 - 很抱歉
- Are you okay? - I'm sorry.
要不要坐一下
Do you want to sit down?
倒茶
Refill.
这孩子真可爱
That's a nice baby.
你真幸运能有这么一个可爱的孩子
You lucky you got such a nice baby.
非常感谢 能帮我把这个热一下吗
Thank you very much. Can you warm this up?
当然 没问题 他叫什么名字
Sure, no problem. What his name, huh?
现在还没起名
No name, not yet.
如今这样
So... here we are.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
这么这么长时间以来
Long, long, long, long time.
你看明白了吗
You see that?
奥克拉死了 我们的孩子诞生了
Okla dies, and our baby is born.
你想以奥克拉给这孩子命名吗
Do you want to name him after Okla?
奥克拉的真实姓名是大卫
Okla's real name was David.
大卫
David.
David?
大卫
嘿
Hey!
我们的孩子 他名叫大卫
Our kid, his name is David.
大卫 大卫是个好名字
David. David good name.
嘿 大卫
Hey, David.
这是什么
What's to it?
点燃它 然后离远点
Light this, then get out of the way.
还不错
Not bad.
我看到了 孩子
I'll see ya, kid.
我可不这么认为 总有些人在学校附近逛
I don't think so. There's something going around the school.
打电话给医生了吗
Did you calla doctor?
- 他必须给她一枪 - 是吗
- He had to give her a shot. - Yeah?
他给了露丝一枪 一天之后她就死了
He gave Ruth a shot. Twenty-four hours, it was gone.
一定是有窃听器之类的东西
Must've been a flu bug or something.
墨西哥[暗号] 我们进去了 谢谢
Mexico. We're in, thanks.
记得给我的咖啡加奶油和糖了吗
Did you remember cream and sugar for my coffee?
我可从没忘记你的奶油和糖
I have never forgotten your cream and sugar.
嗯 胡里奥给地板打蜡了吧
Yeah. Have Julio wax the floor, will ya?
- 这里是绿磨坊 - 弗朗克在吗
- Yeah, Green Mill. - Is Frank there?
稍等 弗朗克
Wait a minute. Frank?
欧斯卡 叫弗兰克来
Oscar, get Frank.
嘿 回来
Hey, come back.
电话
Telephone.
嗯
Yeah?
- 是你吗 - 是 继续
- Is that you? - Yeah, hold on.
- 帮我个忙 - 喂! 坐过去
- Do me a favour. - Psst! Move down.
- 说吧 - 我们准备好了
- Yeah, go ahead. - We are on.
你明白吗
You understand?
是的 我明白
Yes. I understand.
快 快
Come on! Come on!
别动
Give me an excuse! Come on!
从车里出来
Get out of that car!
- 你被制服了 笨蛋 - 因为什么
- You're pinched, jagoff! - For what?
尾灯
Driving without a tail light.
扶他起来
Pick him up, huh?
操
Fuck!
嘿 汽车推销员 尤瑞兹
Hey, car salesman. Urizzi.
现在记住我名字了吗
You remember my name now?
怎么能不记住
How can I not
警察局
since the police department
没雇太多波多黎各人
does not hire too many Puerto Ricans.
嘿 混蛋 我是意大利人
Hey, asshole, I'm Italian!
很高兴见到你 你这婊子养的意大利人
I'm pleased to meet you, ugly wop son of a bitch.
混蛋
You motherfucker!
你这家伙真够意思
You're a stand-up guy.
真是个硬汉
You're a real stand-up guy.
你不说话没人把你当哑巴
You got a mouth. You can take a trimmin'.
你可以把事情弄简单 但你偏不要
You could make things easy for everybody. But no.
你个笨蛋
You gotta be a goof.
你真厉害
You're real good.
不使用暴力
No violence.
绝对专业
Strictly professional.
我有点喜欢你们这些年轻人
I'd probably like ya.
喜欢跑跑步 打打球
Like to go to the track, ball games
之类之类的 你知道吗
stuff like that, you know?
弗兰克 有很多方法
Frank, there's ways of doin' things
可以让大家都满意
that round off the corners
让日子过得更潇洒
make life easy for everybody.
这有什么问题 有很多事可以做嘛
What's wrong with that? There's plenty to go around.
我们知道你要干什么
We know what you take down.
我们知道你有更重要的事
We know you got somethin' major comin' down soon.
但你非要像个傻瓜一样去做那些事
But no, you gotta come on like a stiff prick!
你他妈以为自己是谁
Who the fuck do you think you are?
你是有什么问题 你有什么话要说
What's the matter with you? You got somethin' to say
还是等着让我问你
or you waitin' for me to ask you to dance?
你想过
Did it ever occur to you
为了生活而试着工作吗
to try to work for a livin'?
- 只能你自己干那些事情 - 好吧 你这家伙
- Take down your own scores? - Okay, fuck this guy.
告诉你 你他妈的
Tell you something. I'm gonna be on your ass so much
你那天最好小心一点
you're gonna get careless, and on that day
我会去那个地方
I'm gonna be in that place.
那是你
And that is the last place
想不去的地方 因为无论发生什么
that you want to be, 'cause no matter what happens
我都不会被
I will never, ever take a pinch
你这样的傻逼抓住
from a greasy motherfucker like you.
你他妈的 分分钟剁了你
Motherfucker! I'll kill you right here!
- 走着瞧 笨蛋 - 你他妈从这滚出去
- Dancin' goes two ways, prick! - Get this asshole out of here!
让他滚
Cut him loose.
- 约翰 - 嗯
- John? - Yeah?
追到他了吗
You got eyes? You got him?
是的 信号非常好
Yeah, he's beepin' in good.
好
Okay.
开到路边
Pull over!
他认出我吗了 他停车了
He'll spot us. He's stoppin'.
约翰 他在干嘛
John, what's he doin'?
只是呆在原地放松一下
Just relax and stay put.
追 追 他走了
Hit it! Hit it! He's movin'!
继续
Hit it.
好了 放心 后撤一点 我们追上他了
Okay, relax and fall back. We got him.
我们在你右边
We're right with you.
你觉得他要干嘛
What do you think he's gonna put down?
我不知道 我们最好还是跟在他后面
I don't know. But we're gonna be right on this guy's ass.
这家伙要成为历史了
This guy's gonna be history.
给我咖啡
Gimme some coffee.
- 好了 - 给
- Okay. - Here.
五十伏电压 你找到电话线了
Forty volts. You got a phone line.
电话线
Phone.
保持住 你找到一个
Hold it. You got one.
接上
Hook it up.
继续
Go.
电话线
Phone.
对了
Yeah.
快 再来一个就能打开了
Come on. One more and we open her up.
墨西哥
Mexico.
好了 我们进来了
All right, I'm inside.
线上有没有突波
Any surges on the line?
他们搞定了
They held.
快 我们要拥有这一切了
Come on. We own it.
- 点燃了 - 没呢
- Lit? - No.
好了
Okay.
嘿
Hey!
你应该下来 这儿的水真棒
You should come in. The water's great.
嗯 享受一下吧 我们要回家了
Yeah. Enjoy it now. We're goin' home.
明天我们清点一下 就告诉里欧
Tomorrow we collect. Just talked to Leo.
伙计 真棒
That's great, man.
嘿 玛丽
Hey, Marie.
玛丽
Marie.
我去拿背包
I'll go get the bags.
- 进来坐 弗兰克 - 谢谢 - 过得怎么样
Come on in, Frank. Sit down. How you doin'?
- 过得很好 - 看起来就不错
- Good, good. - You look great.
- 不能更好了 - 孩子 我知道你为什么而来
- Couldn't be better. - I know this is what you're here for, kid.
就是它 米奇 想说什么
That's it. Mitch, what's to it?
你身材这么好 你在圣迭戈呆了多久
Your tan is great. How long were you in San Diego?
- 就几天 - 米奇跟我说了那次行动
- A few days. - Mitch told me all about the score.
说你是魔法师先生
Said that you were Dr. Wizard.
是吗
Yeah?
哈喽 弗兰克
Hello, Frank.
- 剩下的呢 - 别担心
- Where's the rest? - Don't worry about it.
这是什么
What is this?
这是现金部分
This is the cash part.
好吧 你食言了
Well, you're light.
这应该有83万
$830,000 is supposed be here...
我数了 这是什么 70 80 90
and I count, what, 70, 80, 90.
那是因为我用剩下的钱送你去杰克逊维尔市 沃斯堡市
That's because I put you into the Jacksonville, Fort Worth
达文波特市的购物中心
and Davenport shopping centres with the rest.
我很照顾我的兄弟
I take care of my people.
你可以问问这些家伙 文件在你家里
You can ask these guys. Papers are at your house.
它是在一个有限的合作关系上建立的
It's set up as a limited partnership.
普通的伙伴是[国内税收法典]第S章的合作关系 你应该给我该有的公平
The general partner is a sub-chapter S corporation. You've got equity with me.
- 好吧 别把我算在内 - 我觉得我们这样挺好
- Well, count me out. - I thought we had this good thing.
另外 我给你接了个活 六个星期后在棕榈滩
Plus, I got a major score in Palm Beach for you in six weeks.
你在跟我说 还是这屋里的其他人
You talkin' to me, or somebody else walk in this room?
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我的意思是 你在做梦
It means you are dreaming.
今天是发薪日 那些已经结束了
This is payday. It is over.
你知道的 当警察找你麻烦时
You know, when you have trouble with the cops
你会和其他人一样贿赂他们 因为只有这解决方法
you pay 'em off like everybody else, because that's the way things are done.
- 但你解决不了 - 不
- But not you, huh? - No.
他们找不到我 你也找不到我
They don't run me, and you don't run me.
我给了你房子 给了你车 你是我的家人
I give you houses. I give you a car. You're family.
我想应该来串串门 这到底算什么 这
I thought you'd come around. What the hell is this? What...
感激之心呢
Where is gratitude?
我为了什么
Where is my end?
你不能吃着碗里的看着锅里的
You can't see day for night.
我能看到我的钱还在你口袋里
I can see my money is still in your pocket
那些是我付出所应得的
which is from the yield of my labour.
什么感激之心
What gratitude?
从我这里你捞了一大笔
You're making big profits from my work
我冒了险 流了汗
my risk, my sweat
但这些都不算什么
but that is okay
因为我选择了做这笔买卖
because I elected to make that deal
但是现在这买卖到此为止了
but now the deal is over.
我要我应得的 然后就走
I want my end, and I am out.
你怎么不加个工会呢
Why don't you join a labour union?
- 我发誓 - 弗兰克 别
- I am wearing it. - Frank, don't.
发誓啊 傻逼
Do it, slick.
一天之内我要我的钱 否则把你的头塞进菊花里
My money in 24 hours, or you will wear your ass for a hat.
让他从这滚出去
Get him the hell outta here.
要我告诉你吗 我跟你说什么来着
Did I tell ya? What did I tell ya?
他在哪
Where is he?
他在哪 他在哪
Where is he? Where is he?
嘿 巴里
Hey, BETTY?
告诉他
Talk to him!
回答他
Answer him.
回答他 回答他
Answer him. Answer him!
他在和你说话 回答他
He's talkin' to you. Answer him.
- 回答他 - 弗兰克
- Answer him. - Frank!
你被设计了
You're set up!
看
Look.
我他妈的说看看他
I said fuckin' look at him.
看看你朋友怎么了
Look what happened to your friend
因为你要和我唱反调
'cause you gotta go against the way things go down.
枉费我对你一片心意
You treat what I tried to do for you like shit.
不想给我干活 你哪出毛病了
You don't want to work for me. What's wrong with you?
还在我家里放狠话
And then you carry a piece in my house.
你是监狱里出来的废人 还是疯子
You one of those burned-out, demolished wackos in the joint?
你害怕了 因为你一点都不在乎
You're scary, because you don't give a fuck.
但是别拿你在监狱里的那些屁道理来跟我说事
But don't come on to me now with your jailhouse bullshit
因为你不是你那个伙伴
because you are not that guy.
不明白吗 你个傻逼
Don't you get it, you prick?
你有车有房
You got a home, car
有事业有家庭
businesses, family
而我有你这一辈子的生命契约
and I own the paper on your whole fuckin' life.
我会把你老婆丢到大街上
I'll put your cunt wife on the street to be fucked in the ass
任由黑鬼和波多黎各人奸淫
by niggers and Puerto Ricans.
你的孩子也是我的 因为那是我买来的
Your kid's mine because I bought it.
孩子是用钱买回来的 那就再卖掉 也算是你卖的
You got him on loan. He is leased. You are renting him.
我要让你家破人亡
I'll whack out your whole family.
明天人们继续吃着他们的汉堡牛排三明治 也不会知道这儿发生了什么
People'll be eating 'em for lunch tomorrow in their Wimpy burgers and not know it.
你要是按照我说的做
You get paid what I say.
就能得到我说了给你的
You do what I say.
只有我来控制你 没有商量的余地
I run you. There is no discussion.
我要你干活 直到你被烧成灰烬
I want, you work. Until you are burned out
直到你崩溃 直到你死
you are busted, or you're dead.
明白吗
You get it?
你有责任
You got responsibilities.
绑起来
Tighten up and do it.
清理干净
Clean this mess up.
把他从这弄出去
Get him outta here.
回来工作吧 弗兰克
Back to work, Frank.
约瑟夫 马上从这离开
Joseph, get over here right away.
你要去旅行
You're goin' on a trip.
弗兰克
Frank?
什么
What?
把孩子叫醒
Wake up the kid.
嗯
Hmm?
你们要马上离开
You're going away.
这不是本来该有的样子
It's not what was supposed to be.
现在的生活不是想象的那样了
It can't be this way.
你不明白吗
Don't you understand?
不明白
Hmm-mm.
不要带任何东西
Do not take anything.
不要打包 现在就准备
Do not pack. Do it now.
- 我们要去哪 - 不是"我们"走
- Where are we going? - "We" are not going.
- 是你们走 - 去哪 什么 你怎么了
- You are going. - Where? What's wrong with you?
我不明白 那你什么时候来
I don't understand. When are you gonna come?
我不去
I am not.
约瑟夫去哪 你们就去哪
You will work out with Joseph where you're going to go.
这是41万
Here is $410,000.
等等 我们才
Wait. We just...
我们像收藏家一样 才把它拆开放进盒子里
We just disassemble it and put it back in a box
拿去藏起来 不是吗
like an Erector set you just send back to a store?
我爱你 我哪也不去
I love you. I'm not going anywhere.
第一个月你要
You give Joseph $20,000...
给约瑟夫两万块钱
for month number one.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
- 他和你在一起呆一个月 那第二个月 - 我们的这一切难道没有任何意义吗
- He stays with you a month, you give him $25,000 - Doesn't anything mean anything?
你就给你两万五
For month number two.
- 我是你的女人 你是我的男人 - 第三个月给三万
- I'm your woman. You're my man. - $30,000 for the third.
弗兰克 弗兰克 我承诺过
Frank, Frank, I made a commitment.
让你我
To hell with me, with you
还有这一切 都见鬼去吧
with everything.
我把你甩了
I'm throwing you out.
走吧
Get out.
出去
滚
Get out!
弗兰克
Frank?
要不要牛奶
You want some milk?
不用 我不喝
No, I'm okay.
啊
Aah!